Andrew Jackson Donelson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Andrew Jackson Donelson Papers 1779-1943 1813-1869
MSS18721
Donelson, Andrew Jackson, 1799-1871
4,000 items
24 containers plus 1 oversize
6 linear feet
14 microfilm reels
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Lawyer, editor, army officer, diplomat, and presidential secretary. Correspondence, journals, draft messages of Andrew Jackson, diplomatic papers, newsclippings, scrapbook, sketches, photos, and other papers covering Donelson's career as aide-de-camp and secretary to Andrew Jackson, charge d'affaires to Texas, minister to Prussia, editor of the Washington Union, and candidate for vice president. Includes papers of Donelson's wife, Emily Tennessee Donelson, daughter, Mary Emily Donelson, and other family material. Also original documents relating to the ratification of the Constitution by Virginia.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Branch, John, 1782-1863--Correspondence.; Brent, William, 1783-1848.; Brownlow, William Gannaway, 1805-1877--Correspondence.; Buchanan, James, 1791-1868--Correspondence.; Burke, Pauline Wilcox. Pauline Wilcox Burke papers.; Butler, Benjamin F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1795-1858--Correspondence.; Call, R. K. (Richard Keith), 1791-1862--Correspondence.; Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866--Correspondence.; Donelson family.; Donelson, Andrew Jackson, 1799-1871.; Donelson, Emily Tennessee, 1807-1836. Emily Tennessee Donelson papers.; Duane, William J. (William John), 1780-1865--Correspondence.; Eaton, John Henry, 1790-1856--Correspondence.; Eaton, John Henry, 1790-1856.; Eaton, Peggy, 1799?-1879; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845--Correspondence.; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845.; Kendall, Amos, 1789-1869--Correspondence.; Livingston, Edward, 1764-1836--Correspondence.; Martin, James Glasgow. James Glasgow Martin papers.; McLane, Louis, 1786-1857--Correspondence.; Monroe, James, 1758-1831--Correspondence.; Pendleton, Edmund, 1721-1803.; Poindexter, George, 1779-1853.; Polk, James K. (James Knox), 1795-1849--Correspondence.; Randolph, Meriwether Lewis, 1810-1837. Meriwether Lewis Randolph papers.; Taney, Roger Brooke, 1777-1864--Correspondence.; Taylor, Zachary, 1784-1850--Correspondence.; Tyler, John, 1790-1862--Correspondence.; Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862--Correspondence.; Wilcox, Mary Emily Donelson, 1829-1905. Mary Emily Donelson Wilcox papers.; Woodbury, Levi, 1789-1851--Correspondence.
Organizations
Bank of the United States (1816-1836); United States. Army--Officers.; United States. Constitution. 1787.; Virginia. Convention (1788)
Subjects
American newspapers--Washington (D.C.); Cabinet officers--United States.; Constitutional history--United States.; Constitutions--United States.; Diplomatic and consular service, American--Prussia (Germany); Elections--United States--1824.; Elections--United States--1828.; Elections--United States--1832.; Elections--United States--1856.; French spoliation claims.; Nullification (States' rights); Plantations.; Presidents--United States--Election.
Places
Germany--Foreign relations--United States.; Prussia (Germany)--Foreign relations--United States.; Texas--History--Republic, 1836-1846.; United States--Economic conditions--To 1865.; United States--Economic policy--To 1933.; United States--Foreign relations--Germany.; United States--Foreign relations--Prussia (Germany); United States--Politics and government--1783-1789.; United States--Politics and government--1783-1865.; United States--Politics and government--1829-1837.; Virginia--Politics and government--1775-1865.
Titles
Washington union.
Occupations
Army officers.; Diplomats.; Editors.; Lawyers.; Secretaries, Presidential.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Andrew Jackson Donelson, lawyer, editor, army officer, diplomat, and presidential secretary were acquired in 1917 from Bettie M. Donelson, Nashville, Tenn. Small, but important, additions were between 1919 and 1972 by Robert Dyas, of Nashville, and others. In 1942 Pauline Wilcox Burke gave a group of Emily Tennessee Donelson's papers, and in 1948 an album of Mary Emily Donelson's was acquired from the same source. Burke's own notes, photocopies, and transcripts relating to the Donelsons, as well as some original manuscript letters, were bequeathed to the Library in 1954.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Andrew Jackson Donelson are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.dd
Microfilm
A microfilm edition of part of these papers is available on fourteen reels. Consult reference staff in the Manuscript Division concerning availability for purchase or interlibrary loan. To promote preservation of the originals, researchers are required to consult the microfilm edition.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1799, Aug. 25 Born, near Nashville, Tenn.
1805, circa Became ward of Andrew Jackson
1817 Appointed cadet, United States Military Academy, West Point, N.Y.
1820 Graduated, United States Military Academy, West Point, N.Y.
1820 1821 Aide-de-camp to General Andrew Jackson at Nashville, Tenn., and in Florida
1822 Resigned from the army
1822 1823 Studied law, Transylvania University, Lexington, Ky.
1823 Admitted to bar, Nashville, Tenn., and commenced practice there
1824 Married Emily Tennessee Donelson, a cousin Assisted Andrew Jackson in unsuccessful presidential campaign of 1824
1825 1828 Engaged in legal practice in Nashville, Tenn., and farming near Nashville
1828 Assisted Andrew Jackson in successful campaign for presidency
1829 1837 private secretary and confidential advisor to President Andrew Jackson, residing at White House
1836 Death of Emily Tennessee Donelson
1837 Returned to Tennessee
1841 Married Elizabeth Martin Randolph, widow of Lewis Randolph
1844 1845 Chargé d'affaires to Republic of Texas
1846 1848 Minister to Prussia
1848 1849 Minister to Federal Government of Germany
1851 1852 Edited Washington Union
1856 Vice-presidential candidate on the Millard Fillmore ticket, American Party
1871, June 26 Died, Memphis, Tenn.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Andrew Jackson Donelson extend from 1779 to 1943, although they are principally for the period from 1813-1869. Letters received by Donelson constitute the bulk of the papers, but retained contemporary copies and drafts of letters sent are present, as well as transcripts and photocopies. Also included are a letter copybook of Donelson's dispatches from Berlin, 1846-1848, a few drafts of speeches, legal and financial papers, photographs, engravings, and printed matter. The collection is arranged in six series: General Correspondence and Other Papers, Additional Correspondence, Letter Copybook, Miscellaneous Papers, Family Papers, and Printed Matter, Documents and Indexes.
Others represented in the Andrew Donelson Papers by distinct but lesser groups of material are Emily Tennessee Donelson, wife of A.J. Donelson, a volume containing correspondence, journal entries, and photographs; Mary Emily Donelson, daughter of Andrew Donelson, an album, diary, and scrapbook, with some correspondence; James Glasgow Martin and Lewis Randolph, correspondence, journals, and notebooks; and Pauline Wilcox Burke, great-granddaughter of Andrew Donelson, correspondence, notes, and research materials.
The major portion of the collection relates to the Donelson's public life, as a cadet at West Point, military aide and private secretary to his uncle, Andrew Jackson, diplomat in Mexico and Germany, editor, and political candidate. Very few items relate to the Civil War period or to the years thereafter.
Andrew Donelson was closely associated with Andrew Jackson from early youth until the latter's death in 1845. Whenever the two were separated, Jackson would write frequent letters to his nephew, discussing matters large and small. Jackson is, then, a major figure in the Donelson papers, and there are some 250 of his letters in the collection. Many drafts and fair copies of Jackson's presidential messages and proclamations were once a part of the Donelson Papers, but were placed with the Library's Jackson Papers some years ago.
Among the many subjects touched upon by correspondence in the Donelson papers are Jackson's presidential campaigns of 1824, 1828, and 1832, the Eaton affair, the resulting Donelson-Jackson breach, and the subsequent cabinet reorganization of 1831. The move to recharter the Bank of the United States, nullification, the Poindexter incident, French spoliation claims, removal of deposits, and other issues of Jackson's presidency are also subjects of correspondence. There are many letters from office seekers and from others hoping to influence President Jackson through his secretary. Family affairs and plantation matters, especially the management of slaves and the breeding and training of horses, are frequent topics of correspondence.
Donelson's diplomatic career, as chargé d'affaires at the time of the annexation of Texas, and as minister to Prussia and Germany, is developed in correspondence and in the case of Germany, copies of dispatches. His brief political career, with the American Party, is not as fully portrayed as other aspects of his life, and very little is available to document the later years spent out of public service.
A small, but highly unusual, group of material in the collection consists of documents relating to Virginia's ratification of the United States Constitution, 1787-1788. Included is a Dunlap and Claypoole printing of the Constitution with holograph annotations by Edmund Pendleton.
The roster of prominent correspondents in the Donelson Papers is long and varied. Presidents in addition to Jackson represented by correspondence are James Monroe, Martin Van Buren, John Tyler, James K. Polk, Zachary Taylor, Millard Fillmore, Franklin Pierce, and James Buchanan. Many of Jackson's cabinet members are included, such as Edward Livingston, Louis McLane, Roger Brooke Taney, Levi Woodbury, John Henry Eaton, Lewis Cass, Benjamin F. Butler, Amos Kendall, John Branch, and William J. Duane.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in six series:
General Correspondence and Other Papers, 1813-1869
Additional Correspondence, 1835-1894
Letter Copybook, 1846-1848
Miscellaneous Papers, 1785-1849
Family Papers, 1779-1943
Printed Matter, Documents, and Indexes
Container List
Available on microfilm. Shelf no. 14,894
- General Correspondence and Other Papers, 1813-1869 (Box 1-18, Reel 1-9)
  Letters sent and received.
  Bound volumes arranged chronologically. Volumes 17 and 18 are undated. Volumes 1-7 are item indexed.
  Index available in Manuscript Division Reading Room and on Reel 14 of the microfilm.
  - 30 July 1813-3 Apr. 1824 Correspondents include: (Box 1, Reel 1)
    - Calhoun, John C.
    - Grundy, Felix
    - Jackson, Andrew
    - McLemore, John C.
    - Monroe, James
    - Reid, John
  - 4 Apr. 1824-9 June 1829 Correspondents include: (Box 2, Reel 1-2)
    - Boyd, John P.
    - Eaton, John H.
    - Jackson, Andrew
    - Kendall, Amos
    - Lee, Henry
    - Livingston, Edward
    - McLemore, John C.
    - McNairy, Boyd
    - Trist, Nicholas
    - Van Buren, Martin
  - 10 June 1829-16 June 1830 Correspondents include: (Box 3, Reel 2)
    - Anderson, Joseph
    - Boyd, John P.
    - Butler, Edward G. W.
    - Catron, John
    - Fenner, James
    - Gales & Seaton
    - Grinnell, Joseph
    - Jackson, Andrew
    - Lee, Henry
    - McLane, Louis
    - McLemore, John C.
    - Overton, John
    - Swartwout, Samuel
    - Van Buren, Martin
    - Woodbury, Levi
  - 17 June 1830-26 June 1831 Correspondents include: (Box 4, Reel 2)
    - Branch, John
    - Duval, William P.
    - Hamilton, James, Jr.
    - Jackson, Andrew
    - Lee, Henry
    - McLemore, John C.
    - Overton, John
    - Simpson, Stephen
    - Swartwout, Samuel
    - Wickliffe, Charles A.
  - 27 June 1831-11 Dec. 1832 Correspondents include: (Box 5, Reel 3)
    - Bell, John
    - Cass, Lewis
    - Catron, John
    - Coffee, John
    - Desha, Robert
    - Gadsden, James
    - Harvey, William Selby
    - Jackson, Andrew
    - Kemble, Gouverneur
    - Lewis, William B.
    - McLane, Louis
    - McLemore, John C.
    - Swartwout, Samuel
    - Woodbury, Levi
  - 12 Dec. 1832-18 Dec. 1834 Correspondents include: (Box 6, Reel 3)
    - Anderson, Joseph
    - Archer, William Segar
    - Armstrong, Robert
    - Benton, Thomas Hart
    - Call, Richard Keith
    - Cass, Lewis
    - Duane, William J.
    - Duval, William P.
    - Ely, Ezra S.
    - Everett, Edward
    - Gardiner, James B.
    - Gwin, William McKendree
    - Jackson, Andrew
    - Johnson, Richard Mentor
    - Kendall, Amos
    - Lee, Henry
    - Littell, Eliakim
    - Livingston, Edward
    - McLane, Louis
    - Monroe, James (NewYork)
    - Polk, Lucius
    - Porter, James Madison
    - Shepley, Ether
    - Skinner, John Stuart
    - Swartwout, Samuel
    - Taney, Roger Brooke
    - Trist, Nicholas
    - Turnbull, William
    - Van Buren, Martin
    - Whitney, Reuben M.
  - 20 Dec. 1834-16 Dec. 1836 Correspondents include: (Box 7, Reel 4)
    - Buchanan, James
    - Butler, Benjamin F.
    - Call, Richard Keith
    - Catron, John
    - D'avezac, Auguste
    - Dudley, Charles Edward
    - Earl, Ralph E. W.
    - Harris, Carey A.
    - Jackson, Andrew
    - Laughlin, Sam
    - Livingston, Edward
    - McLemore, John C.
    - Mahan, Dennis Hart
    - Mann, Abijah, Jr.
    - Moore, Thomas P.
    - Parris, Albion K.
    - Polk, James K.
    - Skinner, John Stuart
    - Swartwout, Samuel
    - Taney, Roger Brooke
    - Yell, Archibald
  - 17 Dec. 1836-19 Feb. 1840 Correspondents include: (Box 8, Reel 4)
    - Butler, Edward G.W.
    - Carroll, William
    - Cass, Lewis
    - Catron, John
    - Elliott, Jesse Duncan
    - Grundy, Felix
    - Harris, Jeremiah George
    - Jackson, Andrew
    - King, William R.
    - Lewis, William B.
    - McLemore, John C.
    - Nicholson, A. O. P.
    - Polk, James K.
    - Van Buren, Martin
    - Whitcomb, James
  - 20 Feb. 1840-7 Nov. 1844 Correspondents include: (Box 9, Reel 5)
    - Armstrong, Robert
    - Bancroft, George
    - Benton, Thomas Hart
    - Blair & Rives
    - Brown, Aaron Venable
    - Buchanan, James
    - Calhoun, John C.
    - Cass, Lewis
    - D'avezac, Auguste
    - Harris, Jeremiah George
    - Haywood, William H., Jr.
    - Jackson, Andrew
    - Kendall, Amos
    - Laughlin, Sam
    - Lewis, William B.
    - McDuffie, George
    - McLemore, John C.
    - Poinsett, Joel R.
    - Polk, James K.
    - Taney, Roger Brooke
    - Tyler, John
    - Van Buren, Martin
  - 8 Nov. 1844-1 Jan. 1846 Correspondents include: (Box 10, Reel 5)
    - Armstrong, Robert
    - Benton, Thomas Hart
    - Buchanan, James
    - Butler, Benjamin F.
    - Calhoun, John C.
    - Cass, Lewis
    - Claiborne, John F. H.
    - Gadsden, James
    - Given, William M.
    - Green, Duff
    - Heiss, John P.
    - Hemphill, John
    - Houston, Sam
    - Ingersoll, Ralph I.
    - Jackson, Andrew
    - Lewis, William B.
    - McLemore, John C.
    - McLeod, Hugh
    - Polk, James K.
    - Richardson, Willard
    - Roberts, Benjamin Stone
    - Sawyer, Lemuel
    - Smith, Morgan L.
    - Taylor, Zachary
    - Trist, Nicholas
    - Van Buren, Martin
  - 2 Jan. 1846-8 Apr. 1847 Correspondents include: (Box 11, Reel 6)
    - Bancroft, George
    - Bates, Daniel M.
    - Bates, Martin W.
    - Bayard, James A.
    - Blair, Francis P.
    - Branch, John
    - Buchanan, James
    - Canitz, Baron
    - Claiborne, John F. H.
    - Clay, Henry
    - Fay, Theodore S.
    - Gadsden, James
    - Gentry, Meredith P.
    - Haywood, William H.
    - Henshaw, David
    - Ingersoll, Colin M.
    - Ingersoll, Ralph I.
    - Jarnagin, Spencer
    - Johnson, Cave
    - Letcher, Robert P.
    - Lewis, Dixon H.
    - Lowrie, Walter
    - McLane, Louis
    - McLemore, Andrew J.
    - Manteuffel, E.
    - Passavant, W.A.
    - Polk, James K.
    - Schilden, Baron de
    - Schleinitz, Baron
    - Seymour, David L.
    - Van Buren, John
    - Van Buren, Martin
    - Wheaton, Henry
    - Wittgenstein, Prince
  - 9 Apr. 1847-25 Feb. 1848 Correspondents include: (Box 12, Reel 6)
    - Armstrong, Robert
    - Bancroft, George
    - Baring Brothers
    - Buchanan, James
    - Butler, William Allen
    - Canitz, Baron
    - Eaton, John H.
    - Fay, Theodore S.
    - Graham, James Duncan
    - Ingersoll, Colin M.
    - Ingersoll, Ralph I.
    - Lawrence, Abbott
    - Morton, Marcus
    - Rush, Richard
    - Walker, Sears C.
    - Wheaton, Henry
  - 26 Feb.-16 June 1848 Correspondents include: (Box 13, Reel 7)
    - Arnim, Count H. K .K. E. von
    - Buchanan, James
    - Calhoun, John C.
    - Canitz, Baron
    - Gwin, William M.
    - Ingersoll, Ralph I.
    - Mason, James M.
    - Mason, John Y.
    - Ritchie, Thomas
    - Sanford, Henry S.
  - 17 June-15 Dec. 1848 Correspondents include: (Box 14, Reel 7)
    - Armstrong, Robert
    - Arnim, Count H. K. K. E. von
    - Bülow, Count
    - Ellsworth, Henry W.
    - Fay, Theodore S.
    - Paulding, Hiram
    - Sanford, Henry S.
    - Taylor, Zachary
  - 17 Dec. 1848-14 Jan. 1850 Correspondents include: (Box 15, Reel 8)
    - Buchanan, James
    - Calhoun, John C.
    - Clayton, John M.
    - Ellsworth, Henry W.
    - Fay, Theodore S.
    - Lawrence, Abbott
    - Parker, Foxhall A.
    - Paulding, Hiram
    - Sanford, Henry S.
    - Walsh, Robert
  - 17 Jan. 1850-22 Mar. 1869 Correspondents include: (Box 16, Reel 8)
    - Blair, Francis P.
    - Bowlin, James Butler
    - Brownlow, William Gannaway
    - Buchanan, James
    - Call, Richard Keith
    - Cass, Lewis
    - Clay, Thomas H.
    - Clayton, John M.
    - Eaton, John H.
    - Ewing, Andrew
    - Fay, Theodore S.
    - Fillmore, Millard
    - Gentry, Meredith P.
    - Howard, Benjamin Chew
    - Jackson, Andrew, Jr.
    - Johnson, Cave
    - Johnston, John R.
    - Jones, Anson
    - Marcy, William L.
    - Meade, Richard Kidder
    - Seymour, Horatio, Jr.
    - Stanton, Richard Henry
    - Tyler, Robert
    - Webster, Daniel
  - Financial records of Lewis Randolph (Box 17, Reel 9)
    - Lists, statements, receipts
    - Memoranda, speeches, fragments
  - Undated correspondence Correspondents include:
    - Armstrong, Robert
    - Fay, Theodore S.
    - McLemore, John C.
    - Armstrong, Robert (Box 18, Reel 9)
    - Berrien, John MacPherson
    - Boyd, John P.
    - Call, Richard Keith
    - Catron, John
    - Donelson, Mary Emily
    - Fay, Theodore S.
    - Filmore, Millard
    - Godwin, Parke
    - Green, Duff
    - Jesup, Thomas S.
    - McLane, Louis
    - McLemore, John C.
    - Macomb, Alexander
    - Sanford, Henry S.
    - Skinner, John Stuart
    - Taney, Elizabeth M.
    - Van Buren, Martin
    - Webb, James Watson
    - Webster, Daniel
    - Wheaton, Henry
    - Woodbury, Levi
- Additional Correspondence, 1835-1894 (Box 19, Reel 9)
  Letters sent and received
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondents include:
    - Blair, Francis P.
    - Brown, Aaron V.
    - Buchanan, James
    - Calhoun, John C.
    - Cass, Lewis
    - Davis, Jefferson
    - Donelson, Andrew J., Jr.
    - Fillmore, Millard
    - Jackson, Andrew
    - Maverick, Samuel A.
    - Pierce, Franklin
    - Pulitzer, Joseph
    - Spencer, John C.
    - Stephens, Alexander H.
    - Van Buren, Martin
    - Wilcox, Cadmus
    - Wilcox, John A.
    - Woodbury, Levi
- Letter Copybook, 1846-1848 (Box 19, Reel 10)
  Copies of Donelson's diplomatic dispatches from Berlin, nos. 1-85.
  Arranged in numerical (and chronological) order
  - Letter copybook of Donelson's diplomatic dispatches from Berlin, Germany (Box 19, Reel 10)
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1785-1849 (Box 20, Reel 10)
  Speeches, legal papers, and accounts of Donelson. Transcriptions and photocopies of letters of Andrew Jackson, Andrew Jackson Donelson, and others. Also biographical sketches of Jackson, Andrew Jackson Donelson, and Mary Smith Donelson.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Speeches, addresses (Box 20, Reel 10)
  - Deed of mortgage, 1842
  - Donelson vs. Saunders
  - Accounts, 1847-1849, undated, (5 folders)
  - Statistics, tables, etc.
  - Copied correspondence (transcriptions and photocopies), 1785-1849, (6 folders)
  - Biographical sketches
    - Andrew Jackson
    - Andrew Jackson Donelson, (2 folders)
    - Mary Smith Donelson
- Family Papers, 1779-1943 (Box 21-23, Reel 11-12)
  Papers of Emily Tennessee Donelson, Mary Emily Donelson, James Glasgow Martin and Lewis Randolph, and Pauline Wilcox Burke.
  The volume of Emily Tennessee Donelson papers is indexed.
  - Emily Tennessee Donelson papers, bound vol. containing journal entries, letters sent and received (in part, photocopies), and photographs, 1779-1853 received Includes photograph of Bettie M. Donelson that was tipped into the volume after microfilming. For contents see Container 25, Indexes (Box 21, Reel 11)
  - Mary Emily Donelson papers, 1836-1856 (Box 22, Reel 11)
    - Album (including some correspondence)
    - Diary
    - Scrapbook
  - James Glasgow Martin and Lewis Randolph papers, 1818-1846
    - Letters of W. Williams to Martin, 1818-1824
    - Journal kept by Martin, 1843-1846
    - Memoranda books, estate papers, and related matter of Randolph, 1836-1846
  - Pauline Wilcox Burke papers, 1913-1943 (Box 23, Reel 11-12)
    - Correspondence, 1913-1943
    - Notes and sketches concerning Donelson's career, (6 folders)
    - Bibliographical notes
    - Notebooks concerning Donelson
    - Notes on Mrs. Andrew Jackson
    - Sketch of Emily T. Donelson
    - Photographs and engravings, (2 folders)
- Printed Matter, Documents, and Indexes (Box 24-25, Reel 12-14)
  Printed matter and documents relating to the ratification of the Constitution by Virginia.
  The indexes are not part of the collection, but are available in the Manuscript Division Reading Room and at the end of Reel 14 of the microfilm edition.
  - Printed matter (Box 24, Reel 12-13)
    - Broadsides
    - Pamphlets, (2 folders)
    - Newspapers
    - News clippings, (6 folders)
  - Documents relating to Virginia's ratification of the United States Constitution, 1787-1788 (oversize) (Box 25 (OV), Reel 13)
    - Dunlap and Claypoole printing of the Constitution, with annotations by Edmund Pendleton (6 pages in 2 pieces)
    - Pendleton, Edmund, address to the Virginia Convention on the occasion of his being chosen to preside, 2 June 1788 (autograph document, 1 page, with endorsement)
    - Memoranda (excerpts from Journal of the Convention, with other notes by William Brent, Jr.)
    - Journal of the Convention of Virginia, June 1788 (printed by Augustine Davis, 42 pages, with notes in an unidentified hand)
    - Miscellaneous notes relating to documents
  - Indexes Not part of collection. Available in Manuscript Division Reading room (Reel 14)
    - Index to Containers 1-7 (but including all Andrew Jackson items, wherever located in the Donelson Papers)
    - Index to Emily Tennessee Donelson papers